Brahm Gicheru

Software Engineer

brahmg1@gmail.com | 240-277-0500 | Germantown, MD

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Brahm is a Government Contractor with 9+ years of experience looking to move into software engineering. Brahm is experienced in using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JSON, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, React, Node and APIs in projects he has completed in school and personally. Brahm is a sharp professional looking to grow and learn as he deepens his technical skills. Brahm is looking for the opportunity to challenge himself and grow into the professional software engineer he envisions.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, **The George Washington University**, Washington, D.C. Bachelor of Arts in Communications, **Salisbury University**, Salisbury, MD

May 2022 May 2013

TECHNICAL SKILLS AND TOOLS

- Visual Studio, GitHub, Microsoft Office, Adobe Acrobat, Salesforce, and Cognos
- Programming Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, JSON, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, React, Node and APIs

CLEARANCES

- Hold an Active Secret Security Clearance
- ➤ Held a Common Access Card at the Fort Detrick Military Base

EXPERIENCE

Business Operations Consultant Accenture Federal Services

May 2019 - Present Annapolis Junction, MD

- Work as part of a team to support all activities within the project Program Management Office (PMO) of an \$11.5 million contract
- Develop executive level documents, presentations, minutes, developing agendas, and status reports (including both developing PMO status reports and coordinating cross program status reporting)
- Implement new hire onboarding activities and ensure process documentation is up to date
- Scope management, including documenting scope
- Manage and track client deliverables, ensuring deliverables are on-time and on-budget
- Document and enforce Standard Operating Procedures
- Supervise with vendor management and engage directly with representatives from subcontractor companies. Including managing 50+ purchase orders, change requests, and invoice reviews
- Provide on-site workplace solutions support

Business Analyst

May 2017 – June 2018

General Dynamics Information Technology, Inc. (Formerly CSRA Inc.)

Alexandria, VA

- Supported the International Counterproliferation Program (ICP) in the areas of tracking and control and financial management of over \$4 million
- > Tracked labor hours, Other Direct Costs, and travel costs through multiple programs/task orders including International Counterproliferation Program (ICP), Proliferation Security Initiative (PSI), Proliferation Prevention Program (PPP), and Threat Reduction Engagement Program (TREP)
- Assisted with preparation and delivery of client deliverables to the client, DoD Defense Threat Reduction Agency (DTRA)
- Monitored revenue variances and prepared Estimate to Complete (ETC) reports, Estimate at Completion (EAC) Reports, and Burn Rate Chart reports for the Project Managers
- Reviewed and tracked monthly client invoices and monitored over \$10,000 in monthly accruals
- Presented a monthly financial status report to Project Managers
- Wrote and updated project specific Standard Operation Procedures

Program Control Analyst

General Dynamics Information Technology, Inc. (Formerly CSRA Inc.)

November 2015 – November 2017 Frederick, MD

- > Supported the DoD Congressionally Directed Medical Research Programs' (CDMRP) grant review process through multiple programs/task orders in the areas of tracking and control and financial management of over \$4 million
- Processed over 2,000 reviewer payments, reimbursements, and other vendors associated with meeting costs each fiscal year; oversaw and tracked contract deliverables and due dates across multiple task orders including Reconstructive Transplant Research Program (RTRP), Psychological Health/Traumatic Brain Injury Research Program (PHTBI), Defense Medical Research and Development Program (DMRDP), Orthotics and Prosthetics Outcomes Research Program (OPORP), Spinal Cord Injury Research Program (SCIRP), Prostate Cancer Research Program (PCRP), Military Burn Research Program (MBRP), and Vision Research Program (VRP)
- Monitored revenue variances and prepared Monthly Financial Projection reports for the Project Managers
- Assisted with preparation and delivery of client deliverables
- Wrote and updated project specific Standard Operation Procedures
- Tracked and coded transactions; tracked Other Direct Costs (ensured correct charges to projects, reviewed cost reports and researched issues, processed adjustments); reviewed, tracked, and processed preliminary monthly client invoices and made any necessary corrections
- Routed over 2,000 payments to accounting and tracked, reported, and monitored over \$10,000 in monthly accruals
- Worked with Accounts Payable and Finance groups to resolve payments and processing issues

Project Support Specialist

November 2013 – November 2015

General Dynamics Information Technology, Inc. (Formerly CSRA Inc.)

Frederick, MD

- Provided Helpdesk support for the three Cancer Prevention and Research Institute of Texas' (CPRIT) programs: Product Development, Prevention, and Research
- Guided the applicant community through the online submission process for a grant
- > Assisted the grantee community through the online grants management system
- Conducted user acceptance testing of the Application and Grants Management systems before release
- > Responded to e-mail and telephone inquiries for over 100 grant applications each fiscal year for the CPRIT Helpdesk
- > Supported Scientific Peer Review and Grants Management meetings in Texas with duties including setting up meeting rooms before each review and breaking down meeting rooms after each review, presenting technical instructions of the peer review process to the peer review panel, recording scores of each application during the review process, and providing technical support to peer review experts experiencing issues